There you're watching the program with
John Kiryaku and me Ted R. It's
Thursday, August 28th, 2025. Thanks so
much for tuning in. Please like, follow,
and share the show,
>> John. Nice to see you there. You're
looking good.
>> Good to see you. Thanks, man. I'm in um
I'm in the Shannondoa Valley of Western
Virginia where it's gorgeous, so
beautiful. Oh my god, it's fantastic.
Ice some friends.
>> I once had spent an entire month just
driving around West Virginia just
because and I really was happy I did it.
I mean, it was like a state that I
didn't really know much about or had not
I I'd only driven like from a lot from
Dayton to New York through that little
sliver near Wheeling of like I think
it's like 12 miles across or something.
>> Yeah, you're in you're in and out in
five minutes.
>> Yeah, it's very strange. Uh although,
you know, Wheeling's got a couple of
good restaurants at least.
>> All right, so let's get to it. Uh we're
going to be talking about um couple of
stories out of Israel. Um I was
heartened to see that there's a growing
draft resistance movement uh reserveists
who are uh refusing the call up to the
ID uh into the IDF. Some of them are
just tired and don't of the war, but
some of them are resisting because of
moral reasons. Uh we'll get into that.
Um 40 to 50% of some units are no-shows.
So it's kind of a big deal. Uh NPR has a
piece that's really worth reading,
although very disconcerting. We'll talk
a little bit about that about basically
the Biden administration's role in
facilitating, creating, and expanding
the genocide and the famine in Gaza. You
can't possibly read it. And bear in
mind, this is NPR. Uh they you can't
possibly read it and come away and still
defend anything that Joe Biden did. Um
then, uh really interesting story, John.
I want to get your take on this. uh
person buys a a lady buys a TV at at
Walmart, turns it on, and she's looking
in some total stranger's living room.
>> Huh.
>> Yeah. What is up with that?
>> Very strange. Uh Tulsi Gabbard uh burned
a CIA officer. Um, looks like it was an
accident, but I'm I'm sure sure he'll
>> remember in my case.
>> The judge said that she would not
respect mena that it didn't matter if it
was a mistake. If you did it, you did
it. Her exact words were, "Mr. Kiryaku,
you either did it or you didn't do it."
And I think you did it.
>> She went to law school.
>> That tells you a lot.
>> Very strange. Um, and finally, Russia's
being accused of uh sending spy drones
over Germany. So, we'll get into that.
What What do you What floats your boat
the most right now?
>> I'll tell you, I'm the most interested
in this Tulsi Gabbard story. Last week,
and we've mentioned this a couple of
times here on the show. Last week, Tulsi
uh fired 37 CIA analysts, all of whom
had something to do with the national
intelligence estimate, saying that the
Russians had interfered in the uh
presidential election. Uh we know that
they didn't interfere in the
presidential election, but she fired all
37 of them. And we even said on the show
last week that this is career ending
because not only did she fire them, she
revoked their security clearances.
Right? So, if you don't have the
security clearance, you might as well
not live in Washington. Just just leave.
Go back to whatever part of the country
you came from. Okay. She listed those 37
people and the names were carried
everywhere in the media. In fact, I even
said on the show that I recognized a
couple of the names. I didn't recognize
most. I've been out of it for 20 years,
but a couple of the names were senior
senior people
>> who were contemporaries of mine when I
was still at the CIA. Well, it turns out
one of those people was undercover. And
so by releasing their name, Tulsi
violated the Intelligence Identities
Protection Act of 1981,
which is exactly why I went to prison. I
was accused of violating the
Intelligence Identities Protection Act
of 1981.
Tulsi is not going to be prosecuted.
Nobody should be prosecuted for that.
It's probably illegal, unconstitutional,
because it it um squaltches free speech.
U the reason why it's on the books is
that nobody's ever challenged it,
including me, because it was like take
the deal for two and a half years or get
12 to 18 years, and what are you going
to do? You take the deal. So,
>> and so the way it works, right, just to
be clear on this, now you're out
obviously because there you are in in
the Shannondoa Valley, but could you now
you don't have any standing, right, to
challenge
>> I do not have standing
>> because because you're out.
>> Well, no, because as part of the plea
deal, I had to wave my right to appeal
and so it's done for me. When when I got
out of prison, Daniel Ellsberg called me
and he said, "We've got to find somebody
uh to appeal their espionage conviction
so that we can get the Espionage Act
declared unconstitutional." I said, "But
Dan, nobody has standing. You have to
have been charged with espionage,
refused a deal, and convicted of
espionage to be able to challenge it."
And he said, "Jeffrey Sterling has
standing." I said, ' That's true. He
went to trial and clearly didn't commit
espionage, but was convicted of it
anyway.
>> Please remind us who that is.
>> Sure. Jeffrey Sterling was a CIA officer
who um filed a racial discrimination
lawsuit against the agency, and they
came down on him like a ton of bricks,
accusing him of leaking information to
James Ryzen of the New York Times,
information about the Iranian nuclear
program. I believe in my heart that
Jeffrey is innocent. He has told me,
he's looked me in the eye and said, I
was innocent. I believe him. So I called
Jeffrey and said, you know, Dan Ellburg
called me. This is the idea that he has.
And Jeffrey said, I I can't do it. He
said, I don't have the inner strength to
go through any more of it. I just can't
do it. And I said, you're the only
person who has standing.
>> You hear that a lot in in these
situations. Uh, I had several
co-plaintiffs
in the LA Times thing and several of
them were like in their 60s and again
the you know they just didn't have what
it takes. They were just like I'm not
strong enough and frankly anyone you and
I both know what you go through. Yeah.
>> And I didn't judge. I I I was like you
know I I I get it. It could kill you.
>> Yeah. Most definitely. I wanted to say
one other thing too. I've told a story a
couple of times and we've got a question
from Rid about Martha Kesler.
>> I was going to bring that up.
>> Oh, did I ever reconnect with Marth
Martha Kesler after she was fired by
Brennan? Believe it or not, when I woke
up this morning, the first thing I did
was to log on to Man. That's that app
where people ask you questions. Um, and
I had a question and it was from Martha
Kesler's daughter and she said that she
was watching the Patrick Bet David
podcast PBD and she said she was shocked
when I mentioned her mother
and so she's trying to get a fuller view
of of who her mother was when she was at
the agency in these senior positions.
And so I'm going to set up a call with
her. I was fascinated to get a to get a
a text from her. Fascinating. But no, I
never connected. I never reconnected
with Martha Kesler. And she died in
2005.
So I had just left the agency when she
passed away.
>> And also this this is of course a good
question from Frasmataz. Uh could
Scooter Libby have been prosecuted under
the Espionage Act or whoever leaked
Valerie claim? I mean there was a
conspiracy. Dick Cheney was involved.
>> Yeah.
>> Well, it was it was Rich Armadage who
was the um the deputy secretary of
defense who leaked Valerie Pla's name.
Not only could he have been charged with
violating the Intelligence Identities
Protection Act, everybody assumed that
he would be charged, at least with that,
and in fact, he was never charged with
any crime. Scooter Libby never leaked
Valerie Plain's name. He was never
accused of leaking Valerie Plain's name.
He was accused of perjury, and that's
what brought him down.
>> See, this is the thing, though. That's a
good question. This is the thing. The
hypocrisy that goes into these decisions
to charge. If you're one of the uh one
of the swells, one of the inside people,
you can say anything you want, but if
you are an outsider, a dissident uh in
any way, a truth teller in many
respects, uh be prepared for a rough
road.
>> Yeah, that's a that's an understatement
for sure. All right, so what happens? I
mean, can this officer successfully sue
to be compensated? I mean, the career is
over. There's going to be lost income.
Um, I would assume, right? I mean, you
you you know, you you've just been
burned. I mean, or do they just simply
like in Valerie Pla's case, could they
have just assigned her to something
else, not undercover, and she would have
been fine if she decided to stay? How
does it work?
>> Well, see, that's a good question, too.
And that one's not easily answerable
because not only was she undercover, she
was under deep cover. She was a knock, a
nonofficial cover officer. Meaning
instead of saying, "Oh, this is Valerie
Plane. She's a, you know, political
officer at the American Embassy." It was
this is Valerie Plain. She's a curator
at the local art museum. And so it's a
whole different kind of cover. It's one
that you can't come back from. You know,
there are people who are blown all the
time. their cover is blown and okay then
you know you're then you're sent to a
country where you're going to be
declared to the local service for
example when Aldrich Ames um revealed
the identities of more than a hundred
officers they had to be the terminology
is brought in from the cold
>> so they could no longer be undercover
officers in Russia where they were all
assigned at one time or another but they
could do the job in other countries
countries in conjunction in cooperation
with the local intelligence service. One
of one of them was a friend of mine,
Mark Polymoropoulos. Um he was in his
first tour when Ames blew his identity
and he ended up becoming the station
chief in Moscow which was just like a
thumb in the Russian's eye, you know, oh
yeah, you you blew our officer, your spy
blew our officer, now he's going to be
the one in charge of operations against
you. And he was.
>> It's Yeah. I mean, do other countries
roll as spitefully as we do? I mean like
I think about even non you know
espionage related stuff like like we I
forget the guy's name but there was some
Soviet dissident that here in New York
City uh they renamed the street after
him that the so that the Soviet embassy
was on
>> like Seniton
Lane or something like
>> yeah it was it was some someone else but
yeah like that
>> they they did that here at the
>> other countries don't do that right I
mean to
>> yeah yeah they do
>> oh really
>> oh sure yeah they do yeah they'll
they'll have like Malcolm X Boulevard in
in Moscow and you know
>> Oh, this is a good question also from
Reed. Did Joe Wilson know about his wife
being a knock when he married her?
>> Oh, yeah. Yeah. Yeah.
>> Because in the old days, right, like
basically uh you weren't allowed to tell
your spouse and it led to a lot of, you
know, they all a lot of divorces. People
thought that their spouses were cheating
and stuff. Is that basically right?
>> Yes, that is right. And that's that's I
I've told a story before where my my
first wife knew that I was in the CIA,
but that was literally all she knew. She
didn't knew she didn't know anything
else. She didn't know what I did all day
long.
>> She did it first and then just stopped
asking. And then when um when 17
November um assassinated our next door
neighbor and they left a manifesto
saying that they had set out that
morning to kill me instead of instead of
Steven Saunders, the British defense
attaches.
They put me in an armored car and took
me to the embassy and I said, "Wait a
minute. Wait a minute." I said, "I just
dropped off my kids at school. I can't
just go to the go to the uh airport."
And they said, "No, we're going to pick
up your kids. We're going to pick up
your wife." So, they sent a car to pick
up the kids, a car to pick up my wife, a
team packed out our house. But when my
wife got to the airport, I was already
there. And she walked up to me and she
said, "I want a divorce. I'm not doing
this anymore."
>> Oh [__]
>> And that was it. We flew home together
on the same plane.
>> Awkward.
>> And that was the end of our marriage.
>> And it was just she was just freaked out
by the fact that
>> you had this talk about
>> Yeah. How was work? I'd say great.
What'd you do? Nothing. Well, who'd you
see?
>> Yeah. Nobody. And then I go out at
midnight and I don't come back until six
o'clock in the morning. And then I just
shower, shave, and go back to work
again. And she's like like this. What
was her name? Did you have a fun time?
>> You know, stuff like that. And I'd be
like, "Listen, I was meeting with an
Iraqi dude. Do I smell like I've been
with a woman?" And then finally when
they tried to kill me, she was just
like, "Uh, I'm done. No more."
>> Yeah. Well, not everyone's along for
that can go along for a ride like that.
For sure.
>> Um that's that's horrible, though.
>> Uh for sure. Um I guess so. Nothing
much. So, will will um this uh will this
undercover officer, formerly undercover
officer, will they stay at the agency or
do you think they'll uh leave?
>> Oh, no. They were fired.
>> Oh, right. Yeah, they were fired, which
which is like a double whammy, right?
So, not only is your cover blown, but
you can't even put on your resume
that you were, you know, the manager of
a mutual fund or whatever the cover was,
>> right?
>> Because you actually were managing the
mutual fund.
>> Yeah, they should sue.
>> Weren't getting paid for it.
>> Although, good luck suing.
>> Yeah, good luck. Has anyone ever
successfully sued the CIA
>> in civil court?
>> Not that I know of. I mean, there have
been small, you know, sort of
picky kind of victories like you sue for
the right to sue, that kind of thing.
>> Right. Right. Right. Stevie is asking if
we should do it if we can do a Discord
server. Um, my understanding is that
Robbie um is working on that for us,
right?
>> Yes.
>> Yeah. Okay. So,
>> it's a good question. We we need to be
on Discord.
>> Yeah. No, clearly. Um, yeah. Okay. Uh,
wow. I I'm still a little bit blown away
by that story. Um,
>> oh, it was awful. And and Sodon Sin 232
24, thank you very much, man. Thank you
for your generosity. He's got a good
question here. Is Washington DC really
the Game of Thrones with Trump as king
and his cabinet as his lords of the
land? because I'm kind of disturbed by
the CDC firings, but the CDC personnel
and staff are fighting back. I'm I feel
the same way about these CDC firings. Uh
but yeah, I think I would call it Game
of Thrones. One thing that Trump
understands better than than most um
Americans, I think, is that
you can do literally anything you want,
even if it is patently illegal or
unconstitutional
because you know that it's going to be a
while before the case works its way
through the courts and you're ordered to
take it back, right? So, for at least a
little while, you can do anything you
want. Look at this poor um what's his
name? Abrego guy. Uh the the guy
>> Oh, a Kilmar Albrego Garcia.
>> Kilmar Abrego Garcia.
This poor guy is constantly having to
play catchup because the administration
is going after him like every day
knowing that it's unconstitutional,
but they are willing to take their
chances of being at being slapped down.
yesterday he declared his um intention
to uh apply for asylum in the United
States.
>> That was that was a nice slapback.
>> Yeah. I just wonder um Yeah. I mean, I'm
not sure how that works, right? Because
he's suing and asking the judge I I
don't know if a judge can grant asylum.
I thought that was an administrative
procedure through um
>> the Secretary of State.
>> HH Yeah. through uh Homeland Security.
>> Um
All right. So, let's let's talk about
these uh surveillance drones while we're
on the subject of espionage. So, I mean,
you know, I'm old enough to remember
when violating another country's
airspace was considered an act of war.
>> Yeah,
>> that ship has sailed a long time ago
since uh I don't know, you could say
since Gary Powers or uh you know, maybe
and or certainly the US has had spy
planes and drones and satellites over
well, satellites don't really count
somehow. if you're high enough, it's
okay. But but you know, um so first of
all, I guess the question is, you know,
with when it comes to Russia, uh you
know, there's there's uh Russia,
Russophobia is a real thing, you always
have to ask, you know, is it there's a
lot of paranoia. Is this real? Uh and if
so, is it an act of war? And what, if
anything, can the Germans do about it?
>> Um well, I'm going to make an assumption
here that that these were Russian
drones. I would wonder how though they
got over Germany because you'd have to
either cross the whole of Poland to get
there or if they
>> apparently they were they were
apparently launched from ships in the
Baltic Sea.
>> That that would make more sense to me.
Um but um
yeah, an act of war uh not so much as a
violation of airspace, which the
Russians do to us all the time in
Alaska, for example, and we do to them
with some frequency as well, as do the
Norwegians, the Swedes, the Turks.
So, yeah, it's one of those things that
what you do is you have your ambassador
go into the into the um Minister of
Defense's office in Moscow and and lodge
a formal a strongly worded diplomatic
protest, you know, saying like to quote
the Stooges, why
>> I thought you were gonna when you
mentioned the Stooges, I thought you
meant Iggy Pop's first band. Um uh so,
uh another Midwestern reference there.
Uh so we have a question from Srod uh
9216.
Have we talked about Sai Hersh and his
London Review of Books article on Bin
Laden raid before?
>> No.
>> Michelle and I did.
>> Uh
>> yeah, Michelle and I did. Um
>> I'll preface this by saying I have a lot
of respect for Sih. For whatever reason,
he doesn't like me. And I once told him
that's that's cool. We don't have to be
pals or anything, but um we have a lot
of friends in common, so we run into
each other at these events. But um my
problem with Sih
is
is it's it's an ongoing problem with a
lot of what he writes. He is the only
investigative journalist I have ever met
who is willing to publish based on
information from one single source. Mhm.
>> And sometimes it's so great that he wins
the Pulitzer Prize and sometimes it is
so bad and so wrong that he is ridiculed
and ostracized. I I saw him at a
Christmas party recently and he
mentioned that things had gotten so bad
for him professionally that he can only
publish in the London Review of Books.
There is not a single American
publication willing to publish a story
by SISH.
>> Yeah. And I always I always assumed that
was the politics of it, but I mean he's
been on the wrong side of the politics
for a long time.
>> Yeah. For a long time.
>> So, okay. So, I mean, I guess two quick
questions. U Bin Laden raid article.
Basically, he argued that Bin Laden was
taken alive and then uh basically Obama
said basically gave the okay to have him
whacked and then the and that basically
the body was packed up and over the
mountains of Wazeristan basically they
they they threw him out out they didn't
no burial at sea um you know just threw
him out over the mountains uh you know
bye-bye bye-bye Osama.
>> Um so you're you're not buying that one?
>> No, not at all. There were so many
people involved in that operation who
ended up telling exactly the same story
except for the one detail that three
different people took credit for
shooting him. Um, too many witnesses,
too many moving parts. And why would you
just dump a body in the mountains for
some tribesmen to find it and then
>> that was my problem with that.
>> Yeah. bury it at a place of, you know,
veneration that's going to become a
mecca, no pun intended, for uh for every
Wahhabi fundamentalist in the in the
Middle East. It does it doesn't make any
sense.
>> However, I will say that the uh
Nordstream story
>> Yeah.
>> rung more true than not to me.
>> I mean, certainly the official story uh
that we're being told. Um that guy's a
pathy, right? The guy that they that the
that the uh is it the Germans who
arrested him? Um uh well the Germans are
going to are going to prosecute him and
they uh the guy who's under arrest. I
mean the yacht story like I'm a diver.
That can't be true. It just can't be
true. It defies the laws of physics.
It's not
>> exactly right. Oh my god. I totally
agree.
>> But the question is I mean of course uh
that's not true. But is the Saiy story
true? That's they could both be wrong.
>> They could they could both be wrong.
Yeah. It seemed kind of obvious to me
that
this was Nordstream 2 was an operation
that required um not just real expertise
and capability but state expertise and
capability.
>> That's what I think.
>> Yeah. Yeah. And we have a question. Um
did I need authorization from my former
employer when I published my my u first
book? It took me nine months to write
the book and 22 months to get it cleared
and they ended up rejecting 120 pages.
So, yeah, it was it was hard. Everything
I write, I have to send to them for
clearance. But, as the years have passed
since my um since my um arrest um and my
detractors
have either died or retired, uh it's
gotten much much easier.
>> What do you What do you make of the guy
that they arrested? Uh, thank you. Thank
you, Nadia Margaret. Uh, it it was he
was arrested in Italy. So, you know,
what's the story here? Is it possible
that this guy actually had something to
do with Nordstream, too, or he's just a
[__] psy?
>> I can't imagine, Ted. I think he's a
psy. I really do.
>> All right. Yeah, we're we're on the same
page there.
>> We really do. And I feel for the poor
guy, whoever he is.
>> Oh, it's No, it's it's really not good.
I mean, like, so it would you know, what
would be the purpose here? Do you think
the authorities could genuinely be
misled and genuinely think, "Oh, this is
the guy. We really believe this." Or is
it like we're going to come up with a
cover story and just arrest someone who
is convenient for us to arrest? I mean,
how does how do these things go?
>> I I hate to be cynical and I and there's
nothing I hate more than sounding like a
conspiracy theorist,
>> but I think that they found somebody
that they could just take a dump on,
somebody who could take the fall, and
they chose him. Now whether he agreed to
do it for money or he really is just a
psy
destroyed, I have no idea. But this just
seems too convenient for me. Too
convenient. I mean, and also I guess the
other question is like why does the I
mean obviously the German government
decided to look the other way when one
of their main sources of energy got
blown up and and and it it [__] up
their people's ability to get affordable
energy to heat their homes in the winter
and stuff.
>> Um I mean the you have to think that the
German people would not be pleased about
this
>> but still wouldn't the heat have been
off by now? I mean pun intended. You'd
think you'd think that that these
European countries would have fallen
apart by now. It would have frozen to
death during the during the winter. I
remember.
>> I mean, but I what I mean is the heat is
on on the the political heat. Like, you
know, in other words, like they're not
>> collapsed governments. It should have
collapsed governments by now.
>> But they're like also kind of like at
this by this point like why not just
forget the whole thing and pretend like
it never happened.
>> I mean, it's been a few years. Why why
stir it up
as we always say, right?
>> Yeah, it's it's always it's the cover.
Yeah, it's exactly. Don't get in the
way. The cover up, you know, it's the
cover up that gets you in trouble. I
mean, nothing says cover up like, you
know, an al like a like a cover story.
>> Yep. I agree.
>> All right. Well, we we're gonna follow
that with great interest. I mean, the
other thing is it doesn't make any sense
even with their own narrative that he
acted alone.
>> Yeah. So
>> he can't have acted alone. I mean it's
just so
>> Well, he didn't do it.
>> No. No.
>> He's just a random Ukrainian.
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. I mean because I mean I remember
just think Yeah. I mean we could get
into the physics of it if you're
interested, but uh do you dive?
>> I took lessons in the uh in the pool of
the American embassy in 1991. And then I
went diving once in in the Red Sea at
Chararmach, Egypt in like 92. And then I
never went again.
>> I mean, the thing is like, yeah, this
this pipeline was uh I think at about
280 feet of depth. Um
>> and so the thing is, right, so you can a
recreational diver at most can go down
to 130 feet, right? Like that's it.
>> And it's dark and really really high
pressure.
>> Yeah. Yeah. Yeah. Yeah. That 130 is
really dark. So you do an aggressive
descent like you basically go you point
straight down you kick like crazy you
get down there you can the whole dive is
six minutes from there down and back. So
you can basically go putter around for
45 seconds and you have to make your way
up and do your safety stops on the way
back otherwise you die of the bends.
>> That's at 130 ft. Now, because it's
exponential, right, 260 ft is not twice
as hard. It's four times as hard, four
times as much pressure, which means that
your air goes four times faster, which
means you would have at most a minute
and a half to go from top to down to the
bottom and back up. I'm sorry. You're
going to have what? Two seconds down
there. So during those two seconds,
you're going to break the shell of the
pipeline. You're going to install the
plastique explosives. You're going to
leave and be gone before that thing
blows up. And that's at 260 ft. And it
was deeper than that. It's just not
possible. Um I had a a relative, my um
cousin's husband, uh he was a
professional diver in the French Navy.
He used to go down to the bottom of the
Pacific Ocean and install the for the
install nuclear weapons for nuke tests.
Remember when France was still doing
nuke tests well into like the early 80s?
So he was one of those guys, right? And
they would go down to like500 2,000 ft.
But they use submersibles and mixed
gases uh and you know and they have like
15 tanks like lined up side by side. I
mean, it's a whole, like you said,
state. It's a state enterprise, right?
I'm not sure. I mean, maybe like BP can
do stuff like that. You know, maybe the
Nordstream guys could do it. Like, if
you believe the idea that the Russians
blew up their own pipeline, which is
absurd, but but like basically it's just
not possible.
>> No. No, it's not possible. I agree.
Can't do it.
No. Well, all right. So, although I'm
getting push back here from uh Spectrum
says uh you can go to 56.6 meters, which
is about what 100 that's about 200 feet
maybe if you go with 1.6 P2. Okay, sure.
Maybe maybe maybe. But anyway, this is
80 feet down. I mean, it's still there's
no way. Not to mention the time that you
need down there. That's really the
problem here.
>> Yeah. Um,
well, Spectrum's still arguing. All
right, I'm gonna do a deep dive on this.
Pun intended. Um, thank you, Spectrum.
Appreciate it.
Um,
all right. So, we shall see what happens
here. Okay. So, um, Walmart, we're we're
going in reverse order here on the on
the on the uh on this on the stuff. So,
I thought this was really interesting.
So, um, this uh lady goes to Walmart. Uh
she buys a uh a television set. Um she's
a Tik Tocker, so that's how this ended
up breaking up. Her name is Helen
Bratton. Uh she said her friend bought a
Roku TV. Apparently it was previously
owned and then returned. You know,
sometimes you do that like at a box
store or whatever. Happens to me at IKEA
all the time where it's like it was
returned then like pieces are missing.
That's always fun when you're putting
the thing back together. Yeah. Um
because the original owner never lo
logged out of their account, the new
buyer started seeing footage from inside
a stranger's house. So apparently Roku,
this is a quote, has this thing where
you can go and look at the camera
through the TV. So you can monitor your
house and stuff through your TV. She
explained about a week ago things
started popping up at the bottom of the
TV screen at some random person's house
that bought the TV and returned it to
Walmart. The friend couldn't log out
because it required a password to log
out. When she called Walmart, the staff
told her that it was weird and advised
her to perform a factory reset. So, um,
basically the person had logged onto
their account on the TV and didn't log
out, but the video has now seen I mean
this is kind of like crazy that they
didn't do a factory reset. Yeah. and
that the reselling is so common. You
know, I think John about like all the
times I stay in a hotel and uh I'll log
into my Netflix or my HBO Max on the
hotel TV. Uh and you know, I know they
they have a thing good hotels like
Marriott have an automatic reset where
they turn it off. And I don't really
care if people know that I've been
watching I've been binge watching
Banshee lately, but but like you know I
mean this has some to me this has like
these these companies like Walmart need
to get more serious about privacy.
>> Totally totally agree. They need to get
very serious about privacy. And this is
something that's easy to do and it's not
going to cost Walmart anything. Just
reset the TV.
>> Well, it cost them some time, right?
They're going to have to you're going to
have to plug it in and and and and turn
it off, but it'll take like, you know,
five minutes or whatever.
>> You know, I I live with a with a a gay
couple. They're seniors and they they
rent two rooms in my house. And uh when
I came up to New York last week um and
and saw you and and Sean O'Brien
um I was up there for what was it three
four days, Ted.
>> I came back
>> and these guys had ben binge watched
every gay love story movie on Prime. So
I go to I don't Prime and I'm like are
you kidding me? I said, "You guys, every
recommendation I have no movie is some
gay love story.
I tend to I I tend to focus my interest
on on horror and um like award winners,
you know, gives you the the title
award."
>> Yes. Yes. Yes.
>> That's pretty much all I watch. And
documentaries. I watch a lot of
documents.
>> You can create you can get they can
create their own profile on your TV.
>> I said that's what I said. They said,
"Well, you know, we we turned it on and
it just it Prime just popped up." And I
go, "Yeah, but you create your own
profile." See where it says plus?
>> The plus.
>> You're the plus.
>> The plus is for you.
>> Months to to squatchch these gay love
story.
>> Oh my god.
>> Yeah. That's kind of like what you know
that those ads forreutation.com.
Uh I was curious like what do they do
exactly? So let's say there's something
bad about you like uh you know whatever.
uh Ted Ra, you know, did this or that.
So, and that comes and all they do is
they create new content and like flood
flood Google with it. So,
>> bad news down
>> until then. That's all which you can do
yourself.
>> Sure.
>> So, you don't really need them.
>> Yep. Yep. That's right.
>> So, that's what you have to do. Oh my
god.
>> That's what I have to do. It's like
Thanks a lot,
>> Michael broke back streaming.
It's like literally I It's like I wish I
could quit my algorithms, but I I can't.
>> Well, I can't quit you.
>> That's awesome. That's a true to totally
21st century problem.
>> Oh my god, that's so great. Um,
>> okay. Well, now that we're laughing,
let's do let's talk about something less
amusing. Um, unless you're Israeli, you
might find it amusing. So, um, I
actually did kind of find it amusing
that, uh, finally, you know, I've been
kind of deploring how long it's taken
for there to be resistance in, you know,
there used to be a really big liberal
contingent in Israeli politics. That's
right. And um, you know, I used to
always tell people like, no, no, no, no,
like a lot of Israelis are very cool.
They they want the two-state solution.
They want Palestinians to have equal
rights. They don't like the current
situation. But that had hasn't looked
like the case for a long time. But now
um some the so Netanyahu is unleashing
this new offensive against what's left
of Gaza City. Um 60,000 uh reserveists
are being called up. But some units, I
mean only some units, not all of them,
are reporting 40 to 50% no-shows. That's
a lot. Um soldiers are saying, "Listen,
I'm I'm not into the genocide." Or
they're saying, "Listen, this shit's
gone on too long and I'm just done
here." And you know, Israel famously
isn't good at fighting long wars. And
this is officially getting to be a long
war. So, um, it's to the extent that you
can even call it a war. It's kind of a
one-way shooting match. But, you know,
like someone said in the in the in the
chat here much earlier on, the PTSD in
the IDF must be off the charts.
>> It's got to be. It's got to be just out
of control.
Yeah. And, you know, this has happened
in the past. It happened um after the
invasion of Lebanon where the whole
country was gung-ho to go in there and
just wipe out the PLO and then after
they got bogged down,
everybody just wanted to go home.
>> You know, the PTSD really really set in.
>> Um quick quick question here from uh
Nadia Margaret. Could you explain a
cutter's relationship with Egypt and why
on earth the the cutteries would inject
seven and a half billion dollars into
the Egyptian economy?
>> Honestly, to piss off the Saudis, the
Saudis have a very close relationship
with uh with Egypt. They have for a very
long time, at least since the early 19
mid 1960s. And um and the Gutteries
have a terrible terrible relationship
with Saudi Arabia. And so any way that
the guties can just can just get a get a
jab in at the Saudis and vice versa,
they'll do it. So knowing that the
Saudis and the Egyptians are very close,
the cutteries say, "Oh, we'll give money
to the Egyptians and help the
Egyptians." The Egyptians are, you know,
Egypt is called um Adona, the mother of
the earth, right? all Arabs, they say,
sprouted from from Egypt and they know
all it's going to do is piss off the the
Saudis. The Egyptians are perfectly
happy to take the money. The Egyptians,
though, were so close to Saudi Arabia
that last year after the Saudis were
particularly generous with them. They
gave Saudi Arabia this little tiny
uninhabited island in the Red Sea as a
gift to thank them. And the cutteries
are like, "Yeah, let us try to throw a
wrench into that and see what sticks.
That's what it's about.
>> By the way, Marcel is saying on YouTube,
"Fireworks are sort of de facto illegal
in in Israel because people don't use
them because so many people have PTSD."
I have to admit. Uh I have a little PTSD
from Afghanistan and I don't like
fireworks uh for that re exact reason.
Um and um yeah, so yeah, Egypt can't
fail. 110 million people, Houdini says.
Good. True. Um so I mean we're going to
see more of this obviously John um this
is going to be
>> it's going to have an effect um you know
I mean and then also at the same time we
have this article from NPR which is
absolutely devastating right so
basically um a lot of Democratic friends
of ours I'm sure you had them too were
saying look behind the scenes Biden's
doing everything he can he's calling BB
and asking to have food aid come in and
there was devastating chart that they
published that showed that prior to
October 7th, 2023, uh typically about
3,000 trucks worth of aid and other uh
supplies entered Gaza daily. Um that
number plunged uh down to a trickle of
just a few uh ever since then. It never
got higher than 500 ever again. So
obviously um you know we it's not
surprising that uh you know you could
end up with with uh you know with famine
as we have. Uh and pretty much by uh
April of 2024 they were uh the highest
they ever went was 400 trucks a day. Um
Biden meanwhile sent $18 billion in
military aid to Israel.
>> Yeah. Uh, and basically there was a
split inside the administration between
people, the upper echelon, which was
like Tony Blinken, you know, basically
[__] the Palestinians and give the
Israelis everything they want, and then
the lower ranking people in the State
Department who were pissed off and
wanted the administration to lean to cut
off arms and and or at least threaten to
cut off arms. And so now um all told
according to NPR 60,000 of the dead and
so this is higher than the Gaza Health
Ministry estimate um died of hunger
60,000 um mostly children
>> uh and that this was and basically NPR
lays this entirely at the feet of the
Biden administration and now Trump for
continuing it.
>> Um and they talk about the silly
performative stuff like the pier.
remember that,
>> right?
>> And that's what it was performative
>> and the airdrops.
>> Yeah.
>> But like but basically there was no
willingness to and basically the
Israelis behind the scenes including
Netanyahu were constantly telling their
American counterparts, we are not going
to send anything in. Um Netanyahu
apparently told Biden at one point, if I
sent in even four trucks of aid, uh the
IDF tanks would be pointing at me. Well,
maybe we need to take the chance and do
that.
>> I'm okay with that.
>> I'm okay with that as well. Yeah.
>> So, I mean, so to me, there's a lot to
unpack here. So, let's talk about
Biden's legacy. Um, you know, I mean, I
don't think anyone, you know, when Joe
Biden dies, I think this should be at
the top of his obituary. like, you know,
that he he was a, you know, the the
devil's assistant when it came to the
the big the genocide of the 21st
century.
>> That's right.
>> Um and um you know, I mean, how likely
is this to stick to him?
>> I think actually it will stick to him.
History has has a way of evening the
playing field. And I think that that in
the end, this is what is going to be Joe
Biden's legacy. And I think scholars at
the same time are going to look back um
at Joe Biden's very long Senate career
and say even in the Senate he did
nothing to help the Palestinians, hungry
children,
AfricanAmericans.
I mean there are a lot of things that we
can criticize Joe Biden on. This is this
is the worst, but it's one of many. And
I think, you know, in the end, he's
going to go down in history
as the equal of people like, you know,
Calvin Culage or Benjamin Harrison,
people who most Americans would say who,
you know, having accomplished nothing or
or even having made the world a worse
place.
>> Totally. Um, Matthew Blarazz, thank you
very much for your donation, wants to
know, "What differentiates Israel from
other Western supported countries that
commit atrocities?"
>> That's a good question.
>> Good question. It's
>> And I have my and I have and I have the
answer. My the for me the answer is as
an American um the United Israel is the
number one recipient of American foreign
aid. Um, and it is our tightest ally in
the Middle East. So when they when they
kill is when they kill Palestinians,
they do it with US weapons and US money
and their economy is completely propped
up by us. So we're helping. It's not
like if if the uh Myanmar Ha kills the
Rohhinga. That has nothing to do with
us. We're not helping them.
>> I mean, sure, we're not invading to
overthrow the government, nor should we,
but um but that's that's to me the main
difference. Also, I mean, I do think the
Israelis go about this with a certain,
you know, ethnostate, apartheid sort of
mentality that makes them particularly
barbaric.
>> I agree. And one of the reasons why that
bothers me so much is that the the
leaders of Israel, and I'm not talking
about just Benjamin Netanyahu, but I'm
talking about almost all of the leaders
of Israel, whether whether they're
cabinet members or Knesset members or,
you know, the head of the water board
for Hifa or whatever. They're almost
entirely European.
They're not Middle Eastern Jews who have
been in that area for hundreds or for
thousands of years. They're Europeans
whose parents and grandparents
immigrated to Israel and then they just
declared it as their own. This is ours
now. These people who've been here for
all these centuries, they they have to
leave.
>> Yeah. But wait, John, you don't think
it's okay? Like, so I've been Hey,
listen. I've been gone for 1900 years,
>> right?
>> But I'm back, so scooch. Yeah, I'll take
that house. Thank you very much.
>> Yeah.
>> Oh, and let me bulldo your uh your olive
trees that have been there for 300
years.
>> Yeah. No, I mean I I mean I think that's
the I mean I think that that's the
difference, right? Like primarily.
>> Um
also, uh Carter, thank you very much for
your generous donation. Um really
appreciate it. Um look, he's looking
forward to your podcast episode with
Dalton coming up.
>> Thank you. You know what? Dalton just
texted me um the trailer and I haven't I
haven't looked at it yet, but one of the
things I love about Daltton Fischer is
he does literally everything himself.
Ted, you and I couldn't do that. Robbie
talks and I'm like, God bless Robbie
because I don't know what the heck he's
talking about. And he does exactly as he
says he's going to do and he's very
tech-savvy and very helpful and
everything runs smoothly. I couldn't do
that. And Dalton does everything
himself, whether it's cutting and
editing shorts or sound or lighting. His
studio is in his childhood bedroom in
his parents house. And he told me he
spent $15,000
to make it look like a legit
professional studio. That's cool. does.
>> It looks like you went into some, you
know, standalone building that's just
there to be a studio. It looks
fantastic. He's taken this very
seriously.
>> John, this is I'm really glad we got
this question because I really want to
bring this I I really want to answer
this. I'll let you have a shot at it
first. A boreal defit also asked fairly
or it's a commentary. It's the only
democracy in the region by far, John.
>> Okay. You Oh. Oh, no. No, it's not.
>> Do you want to explain why it's not?
>> Uh, yeah. Because only 6% of Arabs are
allowed to vote. It It's It's not a
democracy any more than Kuwait is a
democracy where, you know, only people
who can trace their lineage to the
census of 1920 can vote. Or an Egyptian
democracy where, sure, anybody can vote
so long as you're not too religious.
you know.
>> Yeah. It's like no, I mean, so yeah,
there's not. So, Israeli Yeah, Israeli
Arabs don't have full voting rights.
That's not, you know, we can start
there.
>> But honestly, I'm I'm going to I have to
go to the occupation first. If you
occupy for a long time, I mean, since
1967,
vast swaths of territory. basically you
control uh imagine if the United States
half the population was basically
occupied territory with stateless people
who are not allowed to vote well those
people are under your control it's not
like a to me an occupation is temporary
effectively de facto Israel has annexed
these territories and um and it's been
over half a century and those people
can't vote so most of the people under
your control inside your borders
effectively can't vote By definition,
that's not a democracy as far as I'm
concerned.
>> No, I I agree. It's not a democracy.
>> Um,
thank you, Fasmataz. We love and
appreciate producer Robbie as well.
Producer Robbie is uh off today, but he
will be probably back tomorrow, I would
think. Um, so, yep, much appreciated.
Uh, yeah, Marie Lur says, "Egypt's more
of a democracy than Israel. Yeah,
>> they're persecuted by the US and Israel,
but they are a people with equality
among them.
>> Well, I mean certainly they there are
democratic trappings to to Egypt for
sure.
>> Yeah.
>> I mean although I don't think Cece is
going anywhere anytime.
>> No, that's that's an ongoing problem.
>> Yeah.
>> Uh so who keeps buying this Husbara? We
should talk about what Husbara is,
right? So Nadia Margaret says, "So
Husbara is sort of like it's a it's a
Hebrew word for basically like in I
think it means like to inform or to
explain and um and basically it's a
movement where that that uh is either
organized or in some cases you
self-appoint where basically supporters
of Israel put themselves out on social
media or wherever in any context they
call into a talk show and they basically
try to explain things from Israel's
point of view. Um, and the effect of it
is if you ever notice when you're
swarmed online, when you make a comment
by people who all seem to have similar
talking points, you're being hazbared.
That's what's happening. Um, it's it
might seem like, wow, there sure are a
lot of people out there who really love
Israel, and there are, but the truth is
it's very organized. It's not really as
it's not that organic, really.
>> Yeah. Yeah. You know, I was I I was on
some podcast the other day and somebody
kept saying in the comments like over
and over again, "Don't believe him. He's
a trained fiber. Don't believe him. He's
a trained fiber. He fibs. Everything he
says is a fib." I'm like, "Who the [__]
is this?" And then somebody else wrote
underneath, "John, if you're reading the
comments, ignore the bot."
>> And I was like, "Oh, it's a bot. I
didn't even think of that." And then the
bot didn't respond to it and then after
a while it just stopped.
>> So annoying. Hey, so Drogram show fan
says, "John, you've often said that the
CIA regularly kills people. What does
this actually look like outside of wars?
Who does it?"
>> Yeah, that's a good question. Um, they
try to make it as
clean as possible. I can't even believe
I'm describing it like that.
What that is is um
a team will fly out. Let's say let's say
they get an order to kill, you know,
some Libyan cleric. I'm just making this
up.
>> Sure.
>> Um
they'll do it in several different ways.
Um you can
send in a team in the middle of the
night. They parachute in, you know, to
wherever, 10 miles away. They steal a
car,
drive to the guy's house, discreetly
pick the lock, they they'll have
somebody from the the agency's locks and
picks team, pick the lock, they go in,
and with silenced uh, you know,
suppressors on their on their guns,
they'll they'll just assassinate the
guy. Sometimes they will uh parachute in
or boat in, you know, in the middle of
the night and uh snatch a guy, throw him
in a van, and just drive to the airport
or drive to the boat and, you know, take
him offshore. Um sometimes they'll just
walk up to him in the market and as
they're walking past him, you know,
scratch him with something, some kind of
poison that will kill him in the next
two, three, four hours. Oh, that's like
the famous um KGB killing with the
Russians involved.
>> Do that. Yeah, the the Russians used to
do that a lot and they taught the
Bulgarians to do it all the way into the
early 1980s. That was a favored
Bulgarian assassination technique is,
you know,
>> you come you come home, you feel like
you have a terrible terrible flu
>> catching the flu and then you're dead
the next morning.
>> Yeah, Ryson's crazy.
>> Yeah, Ryson's
a plot point in in Breaking Bad, of
course. Right. And you can make Ryson at
home. I mean, you shouldn't do it
because if you Google it, the FBI is
going to be knocking on your door. Um,
but you
>> not to mention it's very, very dangerous
because it's an alkyoid. So, if it get
even a little bit, you touch it with
your skin, it can get into you.
>> Yes. Just like anthrax.
>> Yeah. So, it's it's not Don't kids don't
try this at home.
>> Don't do that.
>> Do not do this at home. Uh, okay. Um,
yeah. So, thank you firmware for your
donation. Uh, very generous as well.
Israel has an entire government
department uh dedicated to Husbara with
$150 million budget. I 100% believe
that. Uh, Peruse S wants to know on
YouTube um, does the CIA andor other
agencies actively search for compromat
friendly countries just in case there
needs to be some armbanding in the
future?
not that that was they were trending
away from that when I first started at
the agency. Um, in fact, that was a
question that I asked in the operational
training training in the late 1990s. And
one of the uh one of the instructors
said, you know, we only did that because
the Russians did it so frequently, but
we've found that it's just not really
good for source development. If if
you're developing a source and you want
this source to commit espionage for you
or commit treason for you or report to
you from from you know a position in
place in a hostile capital, he's not
going to do it because you're
threatening him, you're blackmailing
him. He's going to do it because he
loves you and you're his best friend or
you're giving him so much money that he
just can't say no. But compromat
doesn't work. in training. One of the
instructors told us a story about um
about hiring a prostitute who lured an
Iranian Ayatollah. Not a senior one.
There are thousands of Ayatollas in
Iran. This is back in, you know,
>> what Ayatollah Ayatollahi,
>> right? Exactly. This is around the time
of the revolution. Um and and she took
him into a a hotel room that was wired
for audio and video. They had sex. the
CIA took uh dozens of pictures of him.
And then when he traveled overseas in
the region to another country, they
confronted him with the photographs and
he says, "Nice work. I'll take two of
those in 8 by10 and give me three of
those in 5 by sevens and oh, can I have
this one uh on a slide so I can put it
on my wall?" And he's like, "You people,
what's the matter with you people?
you're not going to compromise me.
And that was kind of the end of
compromise for the CIA. It just doesn't
work.
>> It doesn't work. So what what happens if
you use it? I mean, do people just leave
or
>> Yeah. They say, "Fuck you." And then
they they
>> so publish and be damned basically.
>> That's super super interesting. Um a
good question actually um in the feed. I
hope it didn't get like pushed up too
far here. Um, Houdini wants to know, "If
the CIA has its own tactical team, why
did why didn't they carry out the Bin
Laden operation instead of SEAL, the
Navy Seals?"
>> Good question. They did. That Navy Seal
team was on loan to the CIA. So, it was
a CIA operation.
>> It was directed by the CIA's
counterterrorism center. And all of the
Navy Seals were temporarily
CIA contractors.
>> Was there ever any chance that Osama bin
Laden could have been captured alive and
brought or brought back to face justice
either at the Hague or in New York?
>> Yeah. Yeah, of course there was. But
Obama said in his memoir, one of his the
three memoirs that um that he made the
decision just to kill him. just kill
him.
>> Is that legal?
>> Oh, yeah. Yeah. If illegal under US law,
if if the president or the president's
representative, who is usually the
national security adviser or the CIA
director, determines that a person is a
clear and present danger to the United
States, any American installation or any
US person, which is an American citizen
or a green card holder,
>> you can kill that person legally.
Yeah. But the president has to order it.
So can so this is the um uh this is the
holder argument right that basically
>> exactly that's exactly what it is.
>> So the president is like a medieval a
feudal lord has the power of life and
death over every other human being on
planet earth.
>> Correct. Isn't that awful?
>> Um that shouldn't be.
>> No no it shouldn't be. So what the CIA
has gone on to do, remember, you know,
the killing of bin Laden was what, 14
years ago.
>> Yep.
>> Um they've developed
a variety of teams. There are teams that
belong to the counterterrorist center.
There are teams that belong to what's
called the Special Activities Division.
Um and now there's something called
global resources.
And you can send any of those three
teams or components of those three teams
pretty much anywhere in the world to
kill who you want to kill. Remember in
2011,
I think it was, the New Yorker broke a
story about John Brennan's what they
called the Tuesday morning kill list
meetings. So every Tuesday morning at 7
o'clock, John
>> Yeah. John Brennan would convene a group
of CIA people at the uh at the White
House and they would come up with a list
of people to kill that week. And so the
teams would go out and do their killings
and then they would all reconvene next
Tuesday at the White House and hear who
they're supposed to kill for that week.
>> These are these are and these are the
same people. These are the the the the
normal people. Um thanks Angela for the
donation. Marble, thanks for that
donation as well. Marble wants to know,
"What are the risks of a country if a
country recognizes Palestine?
What happens? There must be risk."
I'm not so sure.
>> I don't think there's much risk. I mean,
>> remains to be seen. I think
>> I mean, France is doing it, the UK is
doing it, Canada's doing it, Australia
is doing it. Maybe there used to be
risk. What do you think?
>> Yeah, I think there there probably used
to be risk and this is what the Israelis
have done economically.
>> Yeah, sure. the the Israelis have
overplayed their hand. Um, and I think
it's because the US has pretty much put
them up to it. Like, you guys can do
anything you want. You can commit any
atrocity, any crime against humanity,
and you will never lose the support of
the United States.
>> And so, uh, I think they just assume
that the rest of of Europe, uh, you
know, and, uh, and Australia and New
Zealand would go along with that. and
they've crossed a line and now there
actually is a consequence.
>> Philip Blair has a question um or
comment and I want to talk about it a
little bit. Um I was I'm curious because
I'm curious what you have to say, John.
Just like Obama intentionally put Aaron
Schwarz in a situation where he'd likely
take his own life
>> and he did. Aaron Schwarz is was a US
citizen. Um so Aaron Schwarz um
committed suicide. He was a uh basically
a a a militant um pro- libertarian the
internet information wants to be free
guy. And this zealous Bostonbased
federal prosecutor went after him for
basically he broke into Jtore, which is
the academic database um and uh hacked
into it and basically released a bunch
of academic papers, millions of them on
the on his theory that uh information
like that shouldn't be behind a payw
wall. Yeah.
>> Um he did a couple other things too, but
basically he busted into the MIT um uh
server. I know all about this because I
was going to write a book. I So, you
know, I have those those little tiny um
graphic novel biographies of Snowden and
Trump and Bernie and so on. And I my
publisher assigned me to do Aaron
Schwarz. And um when I interviewed um I
tried to get interviews with his family
members and people who knew him, no one
would talk to me. They either didn't
trust me or they um or or they just were
too hurt and and traumatized by what
Erin had done,
>> right?
>> So, um and so there was no there so I
couldn't do the book. I mean, I was very
frustrated because I was like, look,
it's going to be a respectful treatment.
Um the other ones were um and so, you
know, it's kind of like check me out,
you know. But anyway, the point is I did
learn I did do a lot of research and I
did a lot of interviews um with people
who did know Aaron. Um do you think
Aaron was pushed to su I mean do you
think he was just a fragile guy who
would have committed suicide anyway or
uh you know is this kind of a pro a
thing where the government sometimes
pushes someone I I remember thinking
that when the LA Times was going after
me and they were declaring lawfare and
going beyond just defending themselves.
They were really [__] with me and and
pushing the pressure points that they
would have really liked it if I'd taken
my own life. Sure.
>> They that would have been like a a major
like toast down at the old boys club. Um
you know, how do you think they view
things like that?
>> You know, when he um when he took his
life, I gave an interview to Kevin
Gustala
um and Kevin asked me if I was surprised
that Aaron had committed suicide. And I
said, "No, I'm surprised that more
people don't commit suicide."
>> I said, "God knows I considered it and I
actually had made a decision to do it."
And I think my u my wife, my ex-wife
now, um
recognized it.
I She She was going to go to bed one
night and I said, "Oh, I'm going to I'm
going to stay up and watch TV." And she
said, "No, why don't you come to bed?"
I was going to go to the garage and turn
the car on and just lay across the back
seat and she just would not let me stay
up and she forced me to go to bed. So,
she knew what I was going to do. Uh but
yeah, I I think listen when they're
threatening you with 30 years, 40 years,
50 years, or in the case of Julian
Assange, like a hundred years, they
don't have any problem if you if you
commit suicide. It's one less It's one
less piece that they have to
>> pain in the ass.
>> Yeah. Yeah. Yeah. That was a a terrible
terrible loss when when Aaron Schwarz
>> and I would agree um about uh Fasmataz
LA Times is a known government cutout
for sure. Um you know they also helped
to do in u what's his name from the um
from the Mercury News. Um you know who
I'm talking about Gary Webb.
>> Gary Webb. Yeah. The LA Times was was up
front there in terms of they couldn't
find enough spots in his back to sink
the knife into.
>> Oh, yeah. And it was no coincidence that
the Washington Post story and the New
York Times story that just eviscerated
him came out on exactly the same day.
>> Yeah, they coordinate.
>> Sure. Sure they do.
>> Yeah.
>> Um Okay, we probably should wrap it up.
take another question or two, but uh
>> uh how many people is it normal for a
CIA case officer to recruit? Asks oi
matey, how you doing?
>> Also, what happens to you if you spend
months on it and fail to recruit
someone?
>> Yeah, good question.
>> Oh, great questions. So
when I was when I was in Athens,
my station chief pulled me aside one day
and um and he said, "You know, I've been
a I've been an operations officer for 25
years." And in my 25 years, I've
recruited nine sources. And he made it
to the senior intelligence service level
four. Huge, right? Community leader of
the intelligence community. nine
recruitments in 25 years. He said to me,
"You've been here two years and you
recruited five people." And every one of
those people was a badass. Let me tell
you, dangerous criminals, killers. I
wasn't recruiting safe housekeepers,
little old ladies, to make sure that the
safe house is nice and clean when you
need to use it for a meeting. I
recruited badasses.
And I said, you know, it's the craziest
thing. I just have a knack for it.
Like I can I can well hide my disdain
for a person. I may hate you, but you
don't have any idea that I hate you
because we're talking about whatever it
is that interests you. We're talking
about baseball. We're talking about, you
know, the founding of the Popular Front
for the liberation of Palestine or all
the people that went to uh Batter and
Minehof's funerals when they committed
suicide and we could talk about the
theater. We could talk about, you know,
FIFA, whatever you want to talk about,
and I will make it look like I'm your
best freaking friend. And that and
that's why I was successful. Um, I
worked for a guy who made GS-15, which
is the top grade in the GS scale, before
you make it to senior service. God knew
he knew he was never going to make
secret to senior service. But in his 25
years, uh he made one recruitment one.
And it was a guy who reported on Spanish
wheat harvests when that used to be a
thing back in the 80s. Uh he was a
disaster and he made it all the way up
to GS15 with one recruitment. So if you
if you have quality recruitments, you're
going to do just fine.
>> Gotcha. So it's not just about like it's
not like a cop writing traffic tickets.
You just have to get the numbers up. Uh
couple quickies. Uh thanks for the
donation, Marble. Uh is Trump's cabinet
the most unqualified cabinet in modern
times?
>> I'm gonna say I don't know. You know,
there's been some We've forgotten about
some seriously unqualified people. I
mean, my favorite was uh Reagan's
Secretary of Energy, Edwards.
>> Oh, James Watt.
>> He was a Well, that's that's the
>> interior. No, no, that was interior.
>> Yeah. James Watts, who actually hated
the environment. So, that's kind of
>> it.
>> Edwards was a dentist who inexplicably
was running the secret the Department of
Energy.
>> I forgot that. Um, and Reagan had that
weird thing of putting um, you know, so
let's see who didn't he have a a general
as his secretary of state at some point?
Um, or a
>> Alexander H.
>> Alexander Hey, right. He I think he was
the first guy to do that. That's
supposed to be the diplomat spot. Now we
can't get rid of that. Coen Powell it
afterwards.
>> Yeah. Not since George Marshall.
>> Yeah.
>> It's very I always thought that was very
strange. Um,
you know, there's been some there's been
some very [__] up cabinet picks, but I
don't know, maybe in the aggregate. Um,
I don't know. It's it's hard to say. I
mean, the American presidency is
definitely a uh a study in entropy,
>> and a lot of those real clowns um you
know, that we know of from the Bush
years. Um, you know, they they
originated in the Gerald Ford
administration like Dick Cheney and
Donald Rumsfeld.
>> They came of age with Ford. That's true.
So, I don't know if you technically we
would call them unqualified, but also uh
this one's a soft a softball for you
from Myra Gomez. Any news on the book
release, Mr. John?
>> So, I so I texted my um my publisher
yesterday. Let me find it. Yeah, here it
is. I said, "Dude, don't forget about
me. You promised me a contract by
Wednesday. Today is Wednesday." This was
yesterday. And he says, "I Here it is."
his his response. He said, "I haven't
forgotten. Back shortly working on it
today." So, I want to believe him,
>> but I don't know.
>> You're like like Moulder. You want to
believe
>> exactly.
>> All right, guys. We're going to have to
say we're going to have to call enough
deprogramming for today. But the good
news is we'll be back tomorrow at five
o'clock Eastern time as we are Monday
through Friday every week. Now, thanks
so much for joining us. Uh this is
Please like, follow, and share the show.
Thanks for all of your generous
donations and uh we'll see you tomorrow.